[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71e", "question": "What southern city is located on the shores of Lake Pontchartrain?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc85673abc30a8194e188b2", "question": "In the film \"Ghostbusters\", what was the name of Bill Murray's character?", "answer": "Peter Venkman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b7b1e662d71a53651016", "question": "Who painted \"Madonna of the Rosary\", in which St. Dominic has been given a rosary by \"the Virgin\"?", "answer": "Caravaggio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf0", "question": "In Japanese, what kind of common fish is \"maguro\"?", "answer": "Tuna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339574", "question": "In, Santa Baby by Madonna what kind of fur does she want him to slip under the tree?", "answer": "A sable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3bc5ff048f679a45ab37", "question": "What kind of plant stem is soft and green?", "answer": "Herbaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdb", "question": "Who is Cleveland, Ohio, named after?", "answer": "General Moses Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a689", "question": "Which US state is home to the manmade Fort Peck Lake?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f433fa5fdd6dd25324de", "question": "Ornamental railings on a balcony are called what?", "answer": "Balustrade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b55601dd7bf43be5e7cf", "question": "What is Maxwell House coffee named after?", "answer": "A hotel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339724", "question": "What is Elton John's real name?", "answer": "Reginald Dwight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52c", "question": "\"Mach One\" refers to the speed of what?", "answer": "Sound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb72", "question": "What was pictured on the face of the US penny just prior to Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "Indian head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8df7ec223966ae8f885a", "question": "What actor plays M. Gustave in the movie \"The Grand Budapest Hotel\"?", "answer": "Ralph Fiennes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad26", "question": "Mehmat Ali Agca was accused of shooting whom in 1981?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e0a606d333868d34d720", "question": "Where was Cleopatra\u2019s birthplace?", "answer": "Ptolemaic Kingdom of Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb4dd7e83c707845b211b", "question": "Why do snails produce slime?", "answer": "To stick to surfaces", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa9", "question": "What is Diazepam better known as?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d6", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Marble Man\"?", "answer": "Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d66", "question": "Who played the role of TV's D. J. Tanner?", "answer": "Candace Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd9", "question": "What TV show did \"Top of the Heap\" spin off from?", "answer": "Married...with Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523c45736d4be723796b36", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c684", "question": "What sense would you not have if you were anosmic?", "answer": "Smell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5da855951aec824685d88d02", "question": "What team was \"plagued\" by the \"Curse of the Bambino\"?", "answer": "The Boston Red Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b055", "question": "For what crime was Al Capone finally sent to prison for in 1931?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8e", "question": "What Australian city's pro basketball team was called the Devils?", "answer": "Hobart's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071e5d3745b36be73039e2", "question": "Which comic book publisher publishes the \"Revival\" series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899dc260d398dc9cf7a6ae", "question": "Which year did Henry Kissinger receive the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe521881bf59ab7d2e380e3", "question": "How many swimmers are in a medley relay team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1c04f6756c9b30ba1500", "question": "Who was the star of the TV cooking show \"The Galloping Gourmet\"?", "answer": "Graham Kerr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea9308d98002fdd633a4", "question": "With what body part is otology involved?", "answer": "The Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fe", "question": "In the 1990 movie \"Pretty Woman\", Julia Roberts is payed to stay for how long with Richard Gere?", "answer": "One week", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac54", "question": "How many transatlantic trips did the Titanic make before sinking?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c2", "question": "According to popular wisdom, you should only eat oysters in months whose names contain which letter?", "answer": "R", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12c80e39efa6330e0fec6", "question": "The Equator passes through how many countries?", "answer": "13", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d58", "question": "Who created the comic book character Wonder Woman?", "answer": "William Moulton Marston", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cd", "question": "What Mexican revolutionary nearly started a war with the US when he invaded a town in New Mexico in 1916?", "answer": "Pancho Villa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af0", "question": "Who was the first person to say the words \"Live from New York, it's Saturday Night!\"?", "answer": "Chevy Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea32edff048f679a45aaea", "question": "CH3COOH is the chemical formula for what common household item?", "answer": "Vinegar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e2", "question": "What was the maximum number of characters that one can use in a Twitter tweet before they were doubled in 2017?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f25", "question": "In the King James Bible, all but three books of the New Testament end with what word?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdb35ec223966ae8f88f1", "question": "In \"Raiders of the Lost Ark,\" what chases Indy out of the Temple of the Chachapoyan Warriors?", "answer": "A giant rolling boulder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdabbf60b8cce1e6fda705a", "question": "Which financial institution offered their clients \"a piece of the rock\"?", "answer": "Prudential", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7be71877e98cb97778960", "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?", "answer": "White Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ca", "question": "What bird, also known as a Man O'War, can glide for hours without flapping its wings?", "answer": "Magnificent Frigatebird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339018", "question": "The novel \"The Dogs of War\" took its title from which other work?", "answer": "Shakespeare's \"Julius Caesar\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44b", "question": "On August 2, 1876, Jack McCall gunned down which famous lawman?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26e", "question": "What is May's birthstone?", "answer": "Emerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a375", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a0", "question": "Which actress played alongside Arnold Schwarzenegger in the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Sharon Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76643eec85e375820b27d", "question": "In which mountain range is the highest continuous paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946c", "question": "What actor voiced Doc Hudson in the 2006 movie \"Cars\"?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c7944f0f6af5b066631", "question": "Ranidaphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Frogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c074", "question": "What is the regulation height for a pin in Ten Pin bowling?", "answer": "Fifteen inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83d", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the nephrons?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e93a7b2d6f11f394a3b2d57", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Ichigo's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Zangetsu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989a862cb8751d53e7d75f9", "question": "United States' observation of Mardi Gras was started in which city and state?", "answer": "Mobile, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012195a63c99d48cd169af8", "question": "How many bricks were used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "10 million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51bc9ff04d658268c9310", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ea", "question": "On June 25, 1993, Kim Campbell became the first female prime minister of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a497", "question": "Which desert is found in South East Mongolia and Northern China?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c743", "question": "What is the more common term for amblyopia?", "answer": "Lazy eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c7", "question": "What nationality was Rembrandt?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73424eec85e375820b22e", "question": "Who succeeded Al Capone after he went to prison?", "answer": "Paul Ricca and Tony Accardo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad4", "question": "From 1956 to 1965, Bill Cullen hosted the original version of what TV game show?", "answer": "The Price is Right", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a630a2ebb971c1417fb96", "question": "What year did the \"Turbot War\" fishing dispute start?", "answer": "1994", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb3", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Anatevka\"?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a000", "question": "What British TV series featured Eddie \"Fitz\" Fitzgerald and Jane \"Panhandle\" Penhaligon?", "answer": "Cracker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fbc6fe83fe1f2a824c3c", "question": "What's the name given to the unleavened bread that is consumed at Passover?", "answer": "Matzoh, which symbolizes the fact the Israelites were in such a hurry when they escaped, they did not have time for bread to rise.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339543", "question": "Who hosted \"The Hollywood Squares\" between 1986 and 1989?", "answer": "John Davidson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c6749076251badbead3", "question": "In the U.S., the 1920s were often described by what term?", "answer": "The roaring twenties ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339524", "question": "What movie character said the line \"Go ahead, make my day\"?", "answer": "Harry Callahan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a676", "question": "What monument, located in Washington D.C., was once the tallest structure in the world?", "answer": "Washington Monument", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad3", "question": "For what movie did Joe Pesci win an Academy Award?", "answer": "Goodfellas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c402", "question": "A June bug is what type of insect?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c378", "question": "What tool did Charles Moncke invent?", "answer": "The monkey wrench", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9b", "question": "What's the appropriate stage name of musician Richard Melville Hall?", "answer": "Moby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1c62baab681b092921a1", "question": "What car was the focus of the 2009 documentary, \"Love the Beast\"?", "answer": "Ford XB Falcon Hardtop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59c", "question": "Who was the first deaf Miss America, crowned in 1995?", "answer": "Heather Whitestone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff7", "question": "On what TV show did Roger Moore replace James Garner?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2f", "question": "Bernard Marx and Lenina Crowne are the main characters of what novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339712", "question": "What are the names of the children on \"The Addams Family\"?", "answer": "Pugsley and Wednesday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b884", "question": "In sports, what does LPGA stand for?", "answer": "Ladies Professional Golf Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c541", "question": "Icthyologists study what?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f901fa5fdd6dd25324f3", "question": "Who sang a cover of \"Never Can Say Goodbye\" in 1974?", "answer": "Gloria Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b29", "question": "What artistic technique requires painting watercolors directly onto wet plaster?", "answer": "Fresco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339662", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty's monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03eddaa1c9af2684d79a5", "question": "In the classic fighting game series \"Street Fighter\", what does the move \"Shoryuken\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Rising Dragon Punch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba71", "question": "Founded in 1924, what department store\u2019s name includes the street of its original New York City address?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add9", "question": "What year was napalm first used?", "answer": "1944", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8db", "question": "Who won a record eight gold medals at the 2008 Summer Olympics in Beijing?", "answer": "Michael Phelps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a01", "question": "When is Cinderella required to leave the ball?", "answer": "By midnight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e96d06d333868d34d755", "question": "Which is the world's oldest island?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb08b8ecf631c2414a13b62", "question": "What team won the first NBA game?", "answer": "New York Knicks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008bc9cf842fa4c4ba969a", "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta sing \"Sempre libera\"?", "answer": "La Traviata", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f8befa5fdd6dd25324f1", "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b0ea3b964118b2bb3809cf", "question": "What year did the \"ILOVEYOU\" virus began infecting computers worldwide?", "answer": "2000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597ddf7177980686f722d186", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1f", "question": "What British musical made 13-year-old Liam Mower the youngest Laurence Olivier Award-winner in 2006?", "answer": "Billy Elliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d4", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe735e8eec85e375820b255", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth trip on as he jumped on the stage of Ford's Theater?", "answer": "Bunting", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7d", "question": "Who is best known for his painting \"American Gothic\"?", "answer": "Grant Wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a06", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Soundgarden?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ee0308d98002fdd633cf", "question": "What is a strong aversion to beards known as?", "answer": "Pogonophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523dca736d4be723796b48", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febad567e83c707845b20f1", "question": "What is the softest metal at room temperature?", "answer": "Caesium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a88", "question": "Which comic strip character is the owner of a dog named Otto?", "answer": "Sgt. Snorkel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc7", "question": "Which food of the gods gives immortality?", "answer": "Ambrosia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59b", "question": "What Canadian province is home to Pink Mountain, Muncho Lake and Nootka Sound?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338880", "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ee", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Golden State\"?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a780", "question": "What geographical boundary was first surveyed in 1763 by Charles and Jeremiah?", "answer": "The Mason-\u00adDixon Line", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b371e31c3f17ccc40c8e20", "question": "What country is home to the longest street in the world?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5d666ce05a3942286e2a", "question": "Which NFL teams always play on Thanksgiving Day?", "answer": "Detroit Lions and Dallas Cowboys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcd", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"smorgasbord\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b271", "question": "What did \"Glamorous Glennis\" do on October 19, 1947?", "answer": "Broke the sound barrier for the first time", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7d", "question": "Who was president when the agency that would become the FBI was created?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Missouri?", "answer": "Jefferson City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc1160469bb8041d07a073", "question": "Which product has used the ad slogan \"Isn't Life Delicious\"?", "answer": "Life Savers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90cf1f52800b05cac20f07", "question": "What US state receives the most annual rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa5880c73aa70ea0b70b3c", "question": "What is the name of the body of water that the Golden Gate Bridge transverses.", "answer": "John C. Fr\u00e9mont gave it the name \"Chrysopylae\" or \"Golden Gate\" on July 1, 1846.  The strait is commonly called \"Golden Gate\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339883", "question": "In Harry Potter, who is it that reveals to Harry that he is a wizard?", "answer": "Hagrid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff512bfff04d658268c92d3", "question": "What doctrine stated the policy of the U.S. regarding European colonialism in the Americas?", "answer": "Monroe Doctrine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad8", "question": "Who played Dracula in the 1931 film of the same name?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ea0b06d333868d34d759", "question": "After the bombing of Pearl Harbor which brand of potato chips changed its name to Jays?", "answer": "Japps potato chips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e90feced7247dfc0fa00309", "question": "In what year was \"Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone\" published in the US?", "answer": "1998", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f71201dd7bf43be5e835", "question": "In the 1960s, General Mills tried to make what salty snack into a breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Bugles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25f", "question": "In 1966, Johnny Cash briefly shared a Nashville apartment with what other country legend?", "answer": "Waylon Jennings", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339338", "question": "What US state is Sheldon from the TV show \"The Big Bang Theory\" from?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d593745b36be73039d6", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b0ff048f679a45aaa3", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Social evaluation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cabdbb53d1af658864d2", "question": "On what short story was the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\" based on?", "answer": "The Greatest Gift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c737", "question": "What does a lepidopterist study or collect?", "answer": "Butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73e1beec85e375820b271", "question": "In which country might you find Shabu Shabu Nabe?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eae2cf83302ff91e46485", "question": "What animal was the Egyptian God Horus depicted as?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c90cf8052800b05cac20f0a", "question": "What is Sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccad3ec223966ae8f889b", "question": "In 1948, which NBA basketball team did the Harlem Globetrotters defeat which eventually helped break the NBA's color barrier?", "answer": "Minneapolis Lakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600243494be4723ccac22194", "question": "Humbert Humbert is the protagonist and narrator of which controversial novel?", "answer": "\"Lolita\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c860877e98cb977789e3", "question": "Which city is the only capital located on the Rhine River?", "answer": "Vaduz, Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f6", "question": "What actor played the role of Father Vito Cornelius in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Ian Holm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339741", "question": "Peter Marshall was the host of what game show for 15 years?", "answer": "The Hollywood Squares", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396df", "question": "In which country was Nicole Kidman born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16b76f7c52aae91cc07e7", "question": "In which musical did Barbra Streisand disguise herself as a man?", "answer": "Yentl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a4", "question": "Which is the most densely populated country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339848", "question": "What comedian was nickname \"Mr. Television\"?", "answer": "Milton Berle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b2", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the World was situated approximately 50 miles south of modern Baghdad?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59636ac3967692ea851899a0", "question": "Which two cross-border neighbouring cities jointly celebrate July 1 and July 4 holidays with the International Freedom Festival?", "answer": "Windsor and Detroit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d31dbb53d1af6588650f", "question": "What year did the TV special \"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" made its debut on CBS?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51e", "question": "What river runs through both Lyon and Marseilles?", "answer": "Rhone River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af69", "question": "During what war did thousands of Americans invade the shores of Normandy?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a725", "question": "Mount Whitney is the highest peak in which mountain range?", "answer": "Sierra Nevada Range", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3d", "question": "What singer's autobiography was titled \"Man in Black\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339762", "question": "In what movie does an office worker's hypnotherapy go wrong?", "answer": "Office Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa74c73838c5c8a417f36", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338937", "question": "What does the fairy godmother transform into a coach for Cinderella?", "answer": "A pumpkin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a100", "question": "What was the housekeeper's name in the TV series \"The Brady Bunch\"?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9a", "question": "What kind of lunch is the common British pub meal of a piece of Cheddar, crusty bread, and a pickle?", "answer": "Ploughman's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ca", "question": "What is the capital of the United States Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Charlotte Amalie", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b483", "question": "What year was actor Stan Laurel born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40d8c685cf15b733e9893", "question": "In the Simpsons what is the discount on the chocolate in the \"Land of Chocolate\"?", "answer": "Half Price", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338efb", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Michael Henchard?", "answer": "The Mayor of Casterbridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909ccedbb53d1af658864e5", "question": "What branch of Christianity introduced the Advent calendar?", "answer": "German Lutherans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac28", "question": "What two oceans does the Panama Canal ultimately connect?", "answer": "Pacific and Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ad", "question": "Whose scary movie character has the real name of Charles Lee Ray?", "answer": "Chucky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f3", "question": "What year marked the debut of the Volkswagen Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ea88fe83fe1f2a824bf1", "question": "What nickname was given to the serial killer, Jack the Ripper?", "answer": "The Whitechapel Murderer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc0a8ec223966ae8f885d", "question": "What guards the Ark of the Covenant in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63e", "question": "What bird can swim but cannot fly?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f4730dcfb6472aeed499d4", "question": "How many Yahtzee \"bonus\" boxes are on a Yahtzee Score Card?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017370a44491cbd7c5a1783", "question": "Hugin and Munin were raven spirits that accompanied which Nordic figure?", "answer": "The ravens Hugin and Munin (meaning \"thought\" and \"memory\") are said to sit on the shoulders of the Nordic god Odin.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe766aceec85e375820b286", "question": "In which city will you find the Brandenburg Gate?", "answer": "Berlin, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c648", "question": "What is the name of Pluto's largest satellite?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb58155dad637d903c880e", "question": "Venice's famed Bridge of Sighs connects two what?", "answer": "Prisons -- The bridge connects an old prison inside the Doge's Palace to a newer one across the Rio di Palazzo.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa91", "question": "What did the Romans call Scotland?\u00a0", "answer": "Caledonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ed", "question": "Which Quarterback led the Baltimore Ravens to victory in Super Bowl XLVII?", "answer": "Joe Flacco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6b", "question": "In photography, what kind of \"number\" is used to measure lens speed?", "answer": "f", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9093b01dd7bf43be5e88c", "question": "Which planet has the largest ocean in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7161a9e54d890926f6de", "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?", "answer": "Asuncion", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c2f64f032c0db195b488", "question": "What charter did a group of English barons force King John to sign in 1215 at Runnymede?", "answer": "Magna Carta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f5", "question": "What's the common name for batteries that contain zinc and manganese dioxide?", "answer": "Alkaline batteries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c500", "question": "Angora wool is produced from what animal's coat?", "answer": "The Angora rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febad0d7e83c707845b20f0", "question": "Which element is named for a mischievous spirit from German folklore?", "answer": "Cobalt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25961b63e5727cf5a484d", "question": "Celine Dion's \"My Heart Will Go On\" song was featured as the main theme song to which 1990's movie?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392bc", "question": "What road film highlights two buddies' search for freedom on their way to Mardi Gras?", "answer": "Easy Rider", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323283bf195a31e15d7391", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation \"Coma Berenices\"?", "answer": "Berenice's Hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338947", "question": "What is the name for a literary device that combines two words and their definitions into a single new word?", "answer": "Portmanteau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a1e1d67b5a031299b74573a", "question": "The Okapi is native to which country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bf", "question": "As what is \"South West Township\" known in South Africa?", "answer": "Soweto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad60", "question": "The 2008 Summer Olympic Games were held in what city?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the Springfield Elementary lunchlady?", "answer": "Doris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cd", "question": "What is added to white sugar to make brown sugar?", "answer": "molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062cc2c9d816e292245c2e", "question": "To which artistic movement does Paul Gauguin's The Yellow Christ belong?", "answer": "The Yellow Christ\u00a0is a painting that depicts the crucifixion. The techniques used in this painting are typical of\u00a0cloisonnism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa9", "question": "What company invented the floppy disk in 1970?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f87", "question": "What is Dame Margott Fonteyn famous\u00a0for?", "answer": "Ballet dancing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ed", "question": "What TV series, which debuted in 1965, was set in the year 1997?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338981", "question": "What kind of a creature is Rikki-Tikki-Tavi?", "answer": "A mongoose", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339236", "question": "What is the real first name of rock star Prince?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9f", "question": "Which nation's Conquistadors took over from the Incas?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea42f7ff048f679a45ab7e", "question": "What is the sea parrot commonly known as?", "answer": "Puffin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a03", "question": "What disability does Rocky Dennis' girlfriend have in the 1985 film \"Mask\"?", "answer": "She is blind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb03f65ff7d326b622a61", "question": "The Atlas Mountains stretch through which countries?", "answer": "Morocco, Algeria and Tunisia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6016021cfe83fe1f2a824c63", "question": "Which Christian holiday is directly related to the observance of the March equinox?", "answer": "Easter is traditionally celebrated on the Sunday after the first full moon that occurs on or after the March equinox.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a849", "question": "The historic district of Haight-Ashbury is located in what US city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c813fbde8045e48466ce", "question": "What digestive tract illness often is a manifestation of diabetes?", "answer": "Gastroparesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cb", "question": "Which Kellogg's cereal was advertised by Tusk Tusk the Elephant?", "answer": "Choco Krispis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92e", "question": "Where in the body would you find the malleus, incus and stapes?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ae", "question": "A Capuchin is a species of what type of animal?", "answer": "Monkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ecff08d98002fdd633c3", "question": "What is artist Beck's birth name?", "answer": "Bek David Campbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a263", "question": "Alanis Morrisette appeared on what 1980's TV show?\u00a0", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e8fdb24f84e0b9f9ffc7", "question": "What does the name Botswana mean?", "answer": "Land of the Tswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f81", "question": "Which is the only Shakespeare play with the name of an English town in the title?", "answer": "The Merry Wives of Windsor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395db", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of the baseball bat Homer makes himself?", "answer": "Wonderbat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb25", "question": "In the book of Genesis, what is said to measure 300 by 50 by 30 cubits?", "answer": "Noah's Ark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e94cf985ea27d7a1303aecf", "question": "In what year was \"Magic: The Gathering\" first released?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eee", "question": "What happened to Barry Allen after lightning struck the chemicals in his lab?", "answer": "He turned into the Flash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339842", "question": "Who directed the 1986 film, \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab31d0b8cce1e6fda7042", "question": "What celebrity had their dog cloned, twice?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6e", "question": "Approximately how many plain chocolate Hershey's Kisses are there to a pound of chocolate?", "answer": "Approximately 100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aef801dd7bf43be5e785", "question": "What is the International Space Station\u2019s average distance from Earth?", "answer": "240 miles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9f", "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a2", "question": "In what decade was Prince Charles born?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbc", "question": "Patty Duke won an Oscar in 1963 for portraying what popular author?", "answer": "Helen Keller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e93", "question": "Who made his West End debut playing alongside his mother in \"South Pacific\"?", "answer": "Larry Hagman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d4c32596a59cbdfbd3a7", "question": "What is the most commonly broken human bone?", "answer": "Clavicle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eae7df83302ff91e46489", "question": "What is a group of deer called?", "answer": "A Herd", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddc", "question": "Who played the Dark Knight in the movie \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c95ff04d658268c9318", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008e026f4f3bc4a292f862f", "question": "A parody of what song was the first to be used as a NASA wake-up call for astronauts?", "answer": "\u201cHello, Dolly!\u201d (Sent in December 1965 to the crew of Gemini 6, it was retooled \"Hello Wally\" for astronaut Wally Schirra.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4dccd06d333868d34d6fc", "question": "In 1993, Aboriginals in Australia won the right to claim land lost to whom 200 years ago?", "answer": "European Colonists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f7", "question": "Which game series features a demon-slaying character named Dante?", "answer": "Devil May Cry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b212", "question": "Who was assassinated by Dan White?", "answer": "Harvey Milk and George Moscone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f386fa5fdd6dd25324db", "question": "What company developed and manufactured the Pentium microprocessor?", "answer": "Intel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c1ee4f032c0db195b47b", "question": "How many passengers were aboard the Mayflower when it set sail for the New World in 1620?", "answer": "There were 102 passengers aboard the Mayflower, and the crew is estimated to have been about 30.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bd", "question": "The first satellites to visit Venus, Mars, & Mercury were all named what?", "answer": "Mariner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6b", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Michael Knight?", "answer": "KITT", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3ae3c73aa70ea0b70ae2", "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?", "answer": "The White Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae92d2574a5ce6b56b8232", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Mah Na Mah Na\"?", "answer": "Piero Umiliani", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad07", "question": "What year, approximately, was the first beer brewed?", "answer": "6,000 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ef", "question": "In which 1985 film does Michael Palin co-star with a pig?", "answer": "A Private Function", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a210", "question": "Jason Voorhees' mask was molded from which NHL team's goalie mask?", "answer": "Detroit Red Wings", "category": "entertainment"}]